Guide to the Benjamin Everett Jordan Papers, 1896-1974 and undated RL.00651
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- North Carolina Government Branches and Departments Files, 1958- 1972
  - College Projects:
    - A and T State University; College of the Albemarle; Appalachian State Teachers; Asheville-Biltmore; Asheville-Buncombe Technical Institute; Atlantic Christian; Barber-Scotia; Bennett; Brevard; Caldwell Technical Institute; Campbell; Carteret Technical Institute; Catawba; Central Piedmont Community; Chowan; Davidson County; Duke University; East Carolina University; Eastern Carolina; Elizabeth City State; Elon; Fayetteville State; Fayetteville Technical Institute (Box 255)
    - Forsyth Technical Institute; High Point; Isothermal Community; Kittrell; Lees McRae; Lenoir Rhyne; Livingstone; Louisburg; Marion-McDowell Technical Institute; Meredith; Mitchell; Montreat-Anderson; Mt. Olive Junior; North Carolina Central; North Carolina State; North Carolina Wesleyan; Peace; Pembroke State; Richmond Technical Institute (Box 255)
    - Robeson Technical Institute, 1966-1970 (Box 256)
    - Rockingham Community; St. Andrew's; St. Augustine's; Salem; Shaw University; Southeastern Community; Southwestern Community; Southwestern Technical Institute; Wilkes Community; Wilmington; Wilson County Technical Institute; Winston-Salem State (Box 256)
    - University of North Carolina, 1965-1972 (Box 256)
    - Wake Forest University; Warren-Wilson (Box 256)
    - Western Carolina, 1968-1972 (Box 256)
    - Western Piedmont Community (Box 256)
- Miscellaneous Files, 1958-1973
  Correspondence with constituents, personal friends, political supporters, and other Congressional representatives on a wide variety of topics. Divided into General Files (mainly letters from constituents that cover multiple issues), Legislative Files (document individuals' opinions on multiple pieces of legislation), and Personal Files (contain general letters from friends, supporters, and colleagues). Also contains biographical information, a small number of photographs, and several small files documenting miscellaneous aspects of Jordan's Senate career. Arranged chronologically within each subdivision.
  - General: Biographical Information, 1931, 1958-1974 (Box 257)
  - General: N.C. Charter Tercentenary Commission, 1962- 1964, 2 folders (Box 257)
  - General: Photographs (Box 257)
  - General: W. Kerr Scott Memorial Book, 1959 (Box 257)
  - General, 1958-1959, 3 folders (Box 257)
  - General, 1959-1967 Feb., 7 folders (Box 258)
  - General, 1967 Mar.-1968, 7 folders (Box 259)
  - General, 1969-1971 Sept., 5 folders (Box 260)
  - General, 1971 Oct.-1972 Oct. (Box 261)
  - Legislative, 1958-1959, 4 folders (Box 261)
  - Legislative, 1960-1961 July, 5 folders (Box 262)
  - Legislative, 1961 Aug.-1964 Mar., 5 folders (Box 263)
  - Legislative, 1964 Apr.-1966 Apr., 5 folders (Box 264)
  - Legislative, 1966 May-1968, 5 folders (Box 265)
  - Legislative, 1969-1971 May, 5 folders (Box 266)
  - Legislative, 1971 June-1972, 4 folders (Box 267)
  - Personal, 1958 (alphabetical) (Box 267)
  - Personal, 1959, 1961-1972 (alphabetical), 4 folders (Box 268)
- Writings and Speeches Files, 1958-1972
  Speeches and statements, press releases, newsletter, column ("Senator Jordan Reports"), and a few articles.
  - Speeches and Statements, 1958-1959 (Box 268)
  - Speeches and Statements, 1960-1969 Nov., 6 folders (Box 269)
  - Speeches and Statements, 1969 Dec.-1972, 4 folders (Box 270)
  - "Senator Jordan Reports," 1958-1968, 2 folders (Box 270)
  - "Senator Jordan Reports," 1969-1972, 2 folders (Box 271)
  - Press Releases, 1958-1972, 3 folders (Box 271)
  - Writings, 1958-1971 (Box 271)
- Clippings Files, 1958-1972
  Photocopies of clippings, nearly all from North Carolina newspapers, including editorials and editorial cartoons, major news and feature stories about Jordan.
  - 1958-1963 Oct., 6 folders (Box 272)
  - 1963 Nov.-1971 Feb., 6 folders (Box 273)
  - 1971 Mar.-1972, 3 folders (Box 274)
- Photograph Series, 1959 May 25-1972 Dec 7 and undated
  The Photographs Series contains negatives for photographs taken of Jordan while he carried out his Senate duties, 1958-1972. Jordan is the primary subject of each photograph, although several photos feature Jordan with others, most often his wife, visitors, or fellow Senate members, including Sen. John Kennedy and Vice-president Lyndon Johnson.
  - 1959 May 25-1972 Dec 7 and undated, 2 folders (Box 275)
- Oversize Series
  - Maps, 1962, 1968, 1970, undated (Oversize-folder 1)
    Several maps of flood control projects.
  - Campaign advertisement, 1972 (Oversize-folder 1)
    Full-page newspaper political campaign advertisement.